朱滔虽然已经受到法律的制裁
We managed to put Chu Tu behind bars,
可是我们付出的代价也非常大
but the operation was a costly one.
你上一次把人家木屋撞毁了
You destroyed the squatter village,
政府要优先安排几百户人家住官民住宅
and the government had to relocate the families
还要赔偿搬家费
and pay damages.
上次抓朱滔的时候
During the operation,
整个商场被你破坏了
you damaged the shopping centre as well.
光是那盏吊灯
We paid well over a million
政府就赔了一百多万
for the chandelier alone.
我想纳税人应该了解
The taxpayers know police work
维持一个安定的社会是要花钱的
doesn't come cheaply.
可是纳税人的钱
But they don't expect
并不是用来做你个人英雄主义的赔偿金的
to pay the cost of someone's heroics.
对了
Well...
为什么当时有楼梯你不走 你要跳什么灯呢
Why didn't you use the stairs? Did you have to destroy that chandelier?
坏就坏在你的身手太好了
Do you always have to be different?
不错
You're right.
可是我们不需要身手好的警察
The force doesn't need superstars.
而是需要服从纪律的警察
We need disciplined policemen.
我并没有想过抓朱滔会升职啊
I wasn't expecting a promotion.
家驹
Ka Kui,
抓朱滔是重案组合作的结果
the operation succeeded through team effort,
你以为是你一个人的功劳吗
not just because of you.
没把你开除啊
You should be grateful
该拜菩萨了
we didn't fire you.
还有啊
And...
上次你挟持我那件事
The bosses wanted you disciplined
上面要我纪律处分你
for holding me hostage.
我不知道浪费多少口水才说服他们的
I managed to talk them out of it.
那我还得谢谢你了
I'm very grateful.
我觉得你有严重的个人英雄主义
I worry about your individualism.
已经不记得怎么作为普通警察了
You're just a police officer. Don't forget that point.
从今天开始
As of today,
你穿制服
you're back in uniform.
哪里需要人帮忙 你就去哪里
You'll be assigned wherever needed.
那每天风吹雨打太阳晒
You mean he'll be an errand boy?
你可惨了
I think you'll be very busy.
Thank You Sir
有本事抓贼啊 抄 抄 抄
What else do you do besides giving out tickets?
巡逻警员请注意
Calling all units.
工业村十字路口发生交通意外
There's been a serious road accident
请尽快赶到现场
at the Industrial Park.
阿美 你回去吧
May, go home.
我在当班呢
I'm working now.
你不要把我当你女朋友嘛
Just think of me as a member of the public
当我是个普通市民
who wants to
一个普通市民跟警察说说几句话嘛
talk to a policeman.
说什么
About what?
我觉得你当交通警察好威风哦
I think you look very smart in uniform.
小姐 我在当班啊
Stop it. I'm on duty.
我带冷饮给你喝
I've brought you a cold drink.
谢谢
Thank you.
谢谢警察叔叔…
Thank you, sir!
小姐 我不喝
-I can't drink here.
喝一口嘛
-Go on, you need a break.
谁知道你什么时候走得开
If I have a drink,
就是不知道什么时候走得开
pretty soon  I'll  need the toilet.
免得喝了想尿尿
Come on.
怕什么嘛
So what
小姐 你是想我被开除啊
May,  I'll  get into trouble.
勇探 这么恩爱呀 还没升职啊
Hello, superhero! You still haven't been sacked?
你走运 不用陪朱滔坐牢
You're lucky you're not in jail with Chu.
坐牢
You think so?
三个瑞士医生证明我只能够活三个月
Three Swiss doctors said I had only three months to live.
我出来等死啊
It's called compassionate release.
三个月很快嘛
Three months can pass quickly.
光阴似箭
Very quickly.
就是你死了
Even you die
我的老板还没死呢
My boss will be alive long after you're dead.
你这句话有点恐吓成分哦
Don't you know you're threatening him?
是吗 你告我呀
Really? In that case, he can sue me.
你小心点
Just be careful!
开车
Drive on.
家驹
Ka Kui?
家驹 朱滔放出来了
Ka Kui, Chu Tu is out of jail.
你知道就好了
If you'd never nabbed a thief,
我们当警察的 有谁没有抓过人呢
who would you have
这有什么好怕的
to be scared of?
记住
Just remember,
有二十五万皇家警察做你的后盾
there are 250,000 Royal Hong Kong Police at your back.
骠叔 皇家警察有没有二十五万呢
Bill, are there really 250,000 police in Hong Kong?
现在一直在招生啊
We're always recruiting new blood.
你没看见海报
Didn't you see our newspaper ad?
还站在这儿干什么
What are you waiting for?
当班呀
Go on patrol!
Yes Sir
我跟署长说好了
Hey, I've talked to Raymond.
下了班也可以带枪
He said you could carry a gun, even after work.
我今天玩得好开心啊
I'm very happy tonight.
当然了 又看电影 又吃牛排的
The show and dinner were great.
不过我觉得你好像有心事一样
-You don't seem very happy.
谁说的
-Really?
没有啊
I am happy.
我希望你能跟我一样那么开心
I wish you had enjoyed it as much as I did.
你怕朱滔…
-Are you worried about Chu?
不怕 不过小心一点好
-No. But I'm just being careful.
勇探
如果下个星期…
-Maybe next week... -Hey, superhero!
这么早就玩完了
Off duty already?
你来干什么
-What are you doing here?
这里又不是禁区
-I can park here.
交通警察也没权罚我呀
You can't give me a ticket.
一楼B座的风水不错
Yeah, you must have a nice view from Flat B of the first floor.
很舒服啊
-Am I right?
你先上去吧
-Go upstairs.
你怎么知道她住一楼B座
How did you find this address?
这个世界
It's amazing
只要肯花钱
what information
别说是一个地址了
you can get with money.
就算是伤天害理的事
People will do anything for money,
也有人肯做
you know?
你这话是什么意思
What do you mean?
这栋旧楼
There's a narrow stairwell
楼梯又窄
in this building.
如果在转角那儿倒点汽油烧起来
If there ever happened to be a fire,
那可就不得了了
it would spread quickly
巷子又那么点儿
through the building.
被车子挡住了
Because of the narrow access,
消防车也上不来啊
the fire brigade couldn't get in there.
小子 你马子挺正的
Your girlfriend's cute.
好好照顾她呀
You'd better keep a close eye on her.
如果脸被人划两刀 或者被烫伤
If she were to get her pretty ass burnt,
就不好看啰
it'd ruin her marriage prospects.
你个混蛋
Bastard!
拜拜
Oh, hero, I'm so happy!
家驹
Ka Kui.
给你擦擦
Here..
对不起
Sorry.
不要紧
OK
都是我不好
It's my fault really.
当个警察有些仇人 还连累了你
Policemen like me have
如果当警察 连个仇人都没有的话
lots of enemies.
一定是抓不到贼的那种笨警察了
You face threats.
你有没有地方可以暂时住一住
Think you could stay somewhere else for a while?
你担什么心嘛
Don't worry about me.
他们只是吓唬人的
They're just morons.
可是我们在明 他们在暗
No. We'd just stand out while they stayed hidden.
这样啊
Okay, then.
那我搬到阿姨家去住几天 你放心了吧
I'll move to my aunt's and hide out for a while.
不要想那么多了
Don't worry too much about it.
我是在想
But if you drop a vase on him,
如果刚才你用花盆砸他 那我不死了吗
I'll  definitely be the dead one.
阿美
May.
就你自己啊 家驹没帮你搬东西吗
It's you...
东西又不多 我自己搬就行了
I can do that...
其实 我不是反对你跟警察谈恋爱
I'm not against you dating a policeman,
我只是不赞成家驹做事太尽责
but I don't want him to spend
男人尽责才好呢
too much time on his work.
可是警察尽责就有很多仇人
That's why he has lots of enemies
要不然 你也不用搬来搬去了
and you have to move back home.
其实我才不怕呢
Actually, I don't worry at all.
只是免得他担心 迁就他嘛
That way, he doesn't need to worry about me.
他担心是对的
He ought to worry about you.
什么人呢
-Who are they?
就是那些混蛋
-They're the ones from last time.
怎么勇探没有来啊
I guess superhero isn't here.
去斜对面那家餐厅等我
Wait for me in the restaurant.
你来干什么
For whta?
我说过要整死他的嘛
I well kill him...
看到你收拾行李
I just want to
当然来看看你是不是跑路啰
know where you're going.
不关她的事啊
It has nothing to do with her.
这位一定是伯母了
You must be her mother.
蛮风骚的嘛
Am I right?
败类
Bastard!
你说我是败类
You call me a bastard?
你错了
You're wrong!
我是败类中的败类
I'm the bastard son of a bastard!
我不怕你们
-I'm not afraid of you.
不要理他 走
-Don't waste time with him. Let's go.
伯母…
Auntie,
怎么你女儿什么人不爱 爱上个警察
why has your daughter fallen for a cop?
我也为你担心呢
Don't
你住十九楼那么高
You live here?
一不小心掉下来
What if you took a fall while cleaning the windows?
强力胶都粘不起来呀
It would take more than glue to fix you!
打我
Go ahead!
你敢打我
Don't be silly.
我就打你
快把她拉开
-Go away! -Get off!
我打死你
Don't grab my hair!
干什么你
What are you doing?
- 打死你… - 放手…
You're hurting me!
滚开
You bitch!
臭女人…
Easy,
生那么大气干嘛 女孩子嘛
she's just a girl.
混蛋
Count yourself lucky.
如果你不是女人 我一定要你的命
If you were a man, you'd be dead!
小心点
Easy,
阿姨 你要不要紧啊
Are you okay? Auntie!
阿姨
Auntie!
你呀 当个警察 到处惹仇人
It's your job that brings the bad guys here.
害得阿美被人家打
Look. May was badly beaten because of you!
- 阿美 - 早知道阿美不要跟你在一起
I've told you to stop seeing him.
是不是那个混蛋打你
Did John Ko attack you?
不是 是我先打他的
I started hitting him first.
所以他就打我啰
He just hit me back.
害得我屁股跌得疼死了 坐都不能坐
It's very hurt
他怎么知道你搬来这里
How did they know you'd be here?
他跟着阿美回来的
They followed her, that's how.
说要看看 她是不是跑了
They're watching us from across the street.
现在 他们在对面餐厅逍遥呢
Now...
真搞不懂他们到底想干嘛
I wonder what's next.
家驹 你不要乱来啊
Ka Kui, don't!
好啊… 让家驹去骂他们一顿也好
He should go and scold them.
如果只是骂他们一顿
If it's as easy as all that,
那可真谢天谢地了
then  I'll  be relieved.
王八蛋 你不要命了
Idiot! Are you crazy?
你除了会欺负女人还会干什么
What else do you do besides bullying women?
欺负女人是我最喜欢做的事情
It's my favourite hobby.
对不起啊
Sorry
打死他我负责
Get the bastard!
你进过警校 读过法律
You know the law, don't you?
就算人家恐吓你女朋友
They may have threatened her, but an arrest requires evidence.
有足够的证据
Don't you know
你可以抓人
you're a policeman?
我实在忍无可忍了
I got carried away.
忍无可忍不是理由
That's not a good reason!
这也是人类正常的反应嘛
He reacted like anyone else would.
身为警务人员 忍耐力应该比一般人强
He's not anyone else. He's a police officer.
你做的事比流氓还坏
What you've done is disgraceful!
简直是侮辱法律
It's a disgrace to the force.
我可不这么认为
I don't think so.
我觉得身为执法人员
If a policeman fails to respond to a personal threat,
如果有罪犯向我恐吓 而不敢作出反应
that's a disgrace.
才叫侮辱法律
-And it disgraces the law too.
你故意惹事 引人注目
-You're a show-off.
让人家记得你曾经抓过朱滔
You won't let us forget you arrested Chu.
你说吧
You talk me
这件事我跟上面怎么交代
How can I explain this to the chief?
我有个解决的办法
You don't have to.
我辞职
I quit.
你认为辞职是解决问题的办法吗
You think that will solve the problem?
这样也好
Why not?
这个是没有办法之中最好的办法
This is probably the best solution.
我出去了
I'll leave now.
谢谢两位多年来对我的关照
Thank you for your support in times past.
再见
Goodbye.
家驹
Ka Kui.
你辞职也好
If that's your last word...
出去找份有出息的事做
then try to find a less stressful job.
再见
Bye-bye.
我会的
I will.
哼
ggh!
你们警察神气啊 警察了不起啊
You think you can do anything
警察乱打人 那也可以乱杀人了
you want just because you're cops!
你们…
You two...
别那么多废话了 签名吧
Shut up and sign this.
我签你妈的签啊
I'm not signing anything. No way!
我不签 签什么签
I'll  sue you
我要告你们
for every penny
我要你们通通坐牢
you've got.
我有钱 我可以请律师
I've got lots of money.  I'll  get a lawyer.
我不怕你们
I'll  sue you!
不要
No.
打呀
See?
你们看到了 他动手打我
You saw this officer try to assault me.
有种你打死我呀
He wants to beat me up like before,
我这只眼镜就是他打破的呀
when he hit me and broke my glasses.
我瞎了 你赔我一只眼睛
You'll pay for that.
有种你当着这么多人面打我呀
Would you dare to beat me up here?
你动手啊 为什么不敢打呀 你怕了
Come on. What are you waiting for?
你开枪打我呀 我告你… 你等着坐牢吧
Come on. I'm going to sue you. You're going to jail.
现在的年轻人真没人情味
These youngsters have no patience.
骠叔 你怎么搞的嘛
Bill,
我刚才是叫你留着他
why didn't you ask him to stay?
我看你撮啊撮的 我就把他撮走了
I let him go...
撮啊撮啊就是留住他
Now that I know what that gesture means,
下次我会了
I'll remember it.
家驹 什么事嘛
Ka Kui, what's the matter?
你是不是很不愿意我当警察
You don't want me to be a policeman, do you?
谁说的
Of course I do.
我有一警察男朋友 我蛮骄傲的
I'm proud of you.
我做了这么多年 两手空空
What do I have to show for all my time as a cop?
惹来这么多仇人 还连累了你
Just enemies.
家驹啊
There you go!
一个好的警察 一定有仇人的
That means you've done your job well.
如果没有的话呢 只有一个原因
If a cop has no enemies, there can only be one reason.
就是他抓不到贼
He hasn't caught any crooks.
其实我被人家恐吓 我觉得很开心
I'm glad they're out to frighten me.
因为可以证明 你是个好警察嘛
It proves you're a tough, good cop.
你真会安慰我
Thanks for that.
其实我做得心都凉了
But I've had enough.
真的
Really?
你是不是很失望
You're really quitting?
你真的辞职了
Do you...
天下太平了
I'm so happy!
冷静点
Calm down.
她怎么了？
What's with her?
阿美，这些年来我对你的态度都不尽如人意
May, all these years I haven't treated you as well as I should have.
阿美
It's my fault.
这几年我都没有好好陪陪你
I have three month's holiday. Let's go somewhere else to relax!
这下子 我可以陪你出去好好玩玩了
真的 家驹
Ka Kui, you really mean it?
去哪玩啊
Where to,
去…
then?
巴厘岛好不好
-Bali. -Good idea!
好啊
We haven't travelled in years.
我们好几年没旅行了
Right, so let's go.
家驹 我好久没有坐飞机了 我好开心啊
It always feels good to fly on a plane.
谢谢 5540块
-That'll be $5,540, please.
好的
-Right.
我出去走走
I'll see you outside.
收不收信用卡
-Credit card?
收
-Sure.
这份给你们做参考 谢谢
Here's our catalogue, sir.
好 谢谢啊
Thank you. Bye.
- 都办好了 - 嗯
Here you go...
不知道应该带什么衣服去
What clothes should I take?
巴厘岛热死了 还用穿衣服吗
You won't need any in Bali.
你想得美啊
Don't be silly!
哇噻 我一想到坐飞机就开心
I can't believe we're going.
希望这家旅行社不会关门
I just hope they don't rip us off.
它旅行社开得那么大 应该很罩得住的
They're a big company. They're trustworthy.
你别紧张嘛
Well,
名也报了 钱也交了 下刀子也得去了
it's paid for now.
好久没见 上班呢
Let's cross our fingers.
什么事
What...
阿新刚打电话来说 商场有炸弹
We've received
商场有炸弹
a bomb threat here.
是啊 我们不知道该怎么办
-Really? -Yeah.
你帮忙好不好
Can you help us out?
- 我帮你去看看 - 好
-All right, then. -Thanks.
家驹
Ka Kui!
我看看就过来 很快的
I'll  just take a look, all right?
新哥
Sun.
师兄 你来得正好
Just in time.
什么情况
What's up?
商场接到个电话说有炸弹
We got a call about a bomb.
会不会是有人开玩笑
Are you sure it's real?
看起来不像
I don't think the guy was kidding.
他还叫我们所有人立刻疏散
He told us to clear the area.
说十分钟之后就爆炸
We have ten minutes.
有没有通知经理
Really?
经理说当他疯子 少理他
The manager said he's nuts.
这样啊
Okay then
好吧 呼叫总部 疏散人群
Start clearing the building now.
这么多人 怎么疏散啊
There are too many people.
师兄
Dub
如果消息是假的 这个责任谁负啊
If it's a hoax, who'll be to blame?
如果是假的 大不了被刮一顿胡子
I'm used to getting an earful.
如果是真的 后果可不堪设想啊
If it is real, we'll endanger lives.
那倒是
That's true.
那怎么办
What do we do?
我们当真的处理
Consider it real.
呼叫总部 疏散人群
Clear the building. Call headquarters.
警铃在哪里
Where's the fire alarm?
哦 在那边
Over there.
家驹
Ka Kui.
按了警铃走吧 来
We're gonna set off the fire alarm. Come on!
警棍
-Your baton.
师兄 你…
-But...!
有难同当啊
Come on! I'll take responsibility.
跟我来
Follow me.
没事 先生别走啊
Don't panic.
单子已经开了 先生
Don't worry.
别走啊 先生
Come back. I've opened the till already.
付钱了没有
Have they paid?
哦 没事…
I'm OK
哎 小姐 别走啊
What's going on?
哎呀 真要命
It's nothing.
那些人若无其事的 不到临头他们不怕
What should we do? They're not taking any notice.
家驹
Ka Kui!
你们还不走啊 快点走啊 快
Don't stay here. Go on!
商场里面所有的人注意 请你们立刻离开商场
Your attention please. Evacuate the building.
无论是顾客或售货员 都请你们立刻离开商场
Everybody please leave immediately.
我们怀疑商场的冷气管发生火警
There's afire in the building.
请你们立刻离开 谢谢合作
Please leave now.
- 快点去查清楚 - 是
Please leave in an orderly manner.
迅速离开商场
Everybody outside.
小心啊
Be careful.
发生什么事？为什么警报响了？
What's going on? Why is the alarm on?
我们的生意怎么样？
What about our business?
阿辉
-Fay. -What's up?
什么事
Get them out of here.
阿新… 叫他们离开这里
Everybody please leave
好了…你们先不要问了 你们先离开这里好不好啊
This is for your own safety. Go now!
- 拜托你们先离开这里 - 家驹 什么事啊
What about you?
我有事 你先离开这里
I won't be long.
放开我 我的钱已经收好了
You go first.
你们看看里面还有没有人
Check the building.
Yes Sir
顾客吓着了 以后怎么做生意啊
I can't understand this.
你说对不对
It's crazy!
有高级警员来了 我去问问他
I ask for him...
对了 你们谁是负责人 叫他出来
-Who's in charge?
你应付一下
-You talk to them.
请大家先出去
Please leave now.
有什么事情 警方会替你们解决的
The police will take care of it.
家驹 怎么办啊
Ka Kui. Ka Kui!
别担心 我还有点事
I'm all right.
你先回家吧
You go home first.
署长
Hello, sir.
有人打电话说商场有炸弹
Someone called and said there was a bomb in the mall
我不知道是不是恶作剧啊
I don't know if it's a prank
谁按的警铃
Who set off the alarm?
署长 是我按的
It was me, sir.
其他人出去
You may leave.
Yes Sir
你凭什么叫人家疏散
Why did you do it?
署长 记得我在警校学过
Sir, when I was in the Police Academy,
身为一个警务人员
I was taught that public
最重要的责任
safety comes first,
就是保护市民生命财产安全
Is to protect the safety of people's lives and property
你以为皇家警察少了你就完了
You think the Royal police would be finished without you
No Sir
林Sir
Lun Sir
这里没有火警啊
Superintendent, there's no fire,
是你的警员说有炸弹 才叫人疏散的
but your men cleared the building.
知道
Right.
已经找爆破专家了
The Bomb Disposal Unit is coming.
有事再通知你们好了
You won't be needed now.
好的
Right.
是不是有人开玩笑
I hope this isn't a hoax.
骠叔
Uncle Bill.
很难说
So do I,
辛苦了
You've had a long day.
雷蒙
Raymond,
他们说要见最大的那个
they want to see the head man.
要不要我出面去应付
Shall I go?
爆破组呢
-Where's the Bomb Disposal Unit?
就快到了
-On their way.
我这么做是对还是错
Is it right or wrong for me to do this
我怎么知道 我又没试过
How do I do know? Don't ask me.
既然事情已经搞这么大了
Right now,
就假装它是对的好啰
we have to wait and see.
叫大家离开
Tell them to leave.
Yes Sir
调查完了 很快就可以进去
You can go back in very soon.
我的球…
My ball!
现在怎么样啊
How are you doing now
小朋友 给你
-Here's your ball, kiddo.
谢谢叔叔
-Thank you.
爆破专家来了
the Bomb Disposal Unit
如果连个鞭炮都找不到的话
If they don't find anything,
署长就难做了
the boss will blow a fuse.
骠叔 你以为我愿意啊
Uncle Bill, I'm very sorry.
哎呀 这种事情谁…
I'm not...
把水管拉过来
Red alert!
灭火队准备
All units move in.
快
Go on.
救火 救火…
Go and fight the fire.
幸亏没人受伤 总算是不幸中的大幸
I suppose the good news is nobody got hurt.
算过损失没有
What are the losses?
财物损失有保险公司赔偿
The insurance will cover it.
最重要是我们公司的形象问题
I'm more worried about the damage to our image.
我们公关部已经跟报界打过招呼了
I've asked the press to cooperate, and I'm sure they will.
尽量以低调处理
But who did it?
是什么人跟我们公司过不去
And why our company?
我想 没那么复杂
It may not be against us.
可能是一些心理不正常的人做的
It could be someone who's mentally disturbed.
冯先生
Mr. Phone
有人打电话来说
There's a man on the line, sir.
银河中心是他们炸的
-He says he planted the bomb.
快接进来
-Have it put through.
接进来
Put him through.
喂 请说
Hello? Hold on.
冯先生 银河中心是我们炸的
Listen, we planted the bomb in your shopping centre.
我们要1000万
We want$10 million.
如果你们不付的话
Pay up or your other properties
我知道你们名下还有很多产业
will get bombed.
这位先生 慢慢商量
But
1000万不是小数目
it's a huge amount of money.
我要跟董事局开会
We'llneed to call a board meeting.
我给你二十四小时考虑
You've got 24 hours.
最好别报警
And don't call the police.
怎么办
-What do we do, then?
一定是那些无聊的人 吃饱了没事做
-Must be some kind of hoax.
也有可能
Yes.
我们该怎么办
So what do we do?
报警
Call the police.
我们交这么多税
We pay enough taxes.
警方也应该做点事情
The police should do something for us.
给我接警务署长
-Get me through to the chief. -Yes.
雷蒙
Raymond,
你真是走运
you were extremely lucky.
那天商场爆炸 竟然没有人受伤
It's amazing that no-one was hurt
简直是奇迹
in the explosion.
你要谢谢关老爷
Thank God for that.
上次朱滔那件案子办得也不错嘛
And the Chu case... well done!
这些不是我一个人的功劳
-Thank you. But it wasn't just me.
那倒是
-That's right.
雷蒙 你不用谦虚了
You've proven yourself.
这件案子还是交给你办吧
You should handle this case.
大家的意思怎么样
Do you agree?
- 好 - 好
-Sure. -Of course.
骠叔
UC. Biu
Morning Sir
看来这件案子挺麻烦的
This is a very tough case.
不麻烦的 也轮不到我们啊
That's why they gave it to us.
你觉得重案组
Who in our department
谁可以办这件案子呢
do you think can solve it?
除了你 我想不出第二个
You're the only one.
再想清楚点
I want a better idea.
总不可能是我呀
It's definitely not me.
比如调了职的…
Maybe we could bring back
或者是那些不干了的
somebody who's on leave.
你不是说陈家驹吧
Do you mean somebody like Ka Kui?
他办案子不错
He has substantial experience.
不行啊
I don't know.
他做事太冲动 又不守规矩
He's unorthodox, impulsive.
有他在 我们一定背黑锅
He'll only give us trouble. We have to bear the responsibility.
我知道 他做事虽然鲁莽了一点
I agree he's a little bit rash,
可是他帮得了大忙
but underneath he's a good cop.
如果你不怕背黑锅
If you're not afraid of the black pot
你自己去找他
Go find him yourself
哎 骠叔
…Ah, uncle pu
叫我做烂…
Let's see who's the boss.
- 那行 那行 - 这行啊
-Over there. -Here?
绑安全带
Fasten your seat belt, please.
哎呀 我忘了买太阳油了
I forgot the sunscreen!
- 到那边再买 - 再买
Buy it when we get there.
你的护照读书的时候拿的
Did you get your passport when you were younger?
亲爱的
Honny!
麻烦你帮我叫一位乘客陈家驹出来一下
Put out a call for Detective Chan Ka Kui.
好
Sure.
各位旅客请注意
Your attention, please.
陈家驹先生请立刻跟我们服务员联络
Will Chan Ka Kui... Let me see. No, don't look!
- 各位旅客请注意 - 我要看 看看嘛
-It's cute. -It's horrible.
- 不要了 - 陈家驹先生请立刻跟我们服务员联络
Ka Kui please contact us.
我过去一下
I won't be long.
- 你是陈先生 - 是啊
-Are you Mr. Chan? -Yeah.
陈先生是吗
Mr. Chan
你的护照有点问题
I'm afraid there seems to be a problem
麻烦你现在跟我下去一趟
with your passport.
我的护照有问题
Really?
很快 例行检查
It'll just be a quick check.
什么事啊
What's going on?
我很快就回来
I'll  be back right away.
OK
拜拜
Bye.
是你们
What do you want?
谢谢你啊
-Thank you.
不客气
-You're welcome.
什么事啊 我要赶着上飞机
What is it? I have a plane waiting.
那天那件炸弹案呢
What about the bomb that day
事实上是一件勒索案
It's actually a blackmail case
跟我有什么关系
What does it have to do with me
这件案子很有挑战性
This case is very challenging
署长的意思是…
Raymond was hoping...
我的意思是 希望你撤销辞职
I was hoping that you might cancel your holiday.
不可能
No!
我已经上飞机了
I've already boarded the plane.
再说我已经离开警队
Plus, I've quit.
我很了解你的心情
I know how you feel.
也很同情你在警队所受的压力
You've been under a lot of pressure lately.
可是逃避不是办法
-But ducking out like this?
我没有逃避
-I'm not ducking out.
骠叔你看 家驹没逃避嘛
He said he's not ducking out!
署长他一向欣赏你的长处
Raymond is a great admirer of your abilities.
我没什么长处
I don't have any abilities.
做事只会冲动
I'm too impulsive.
有冲动 才会有冲劲
Impulsive? More like... a man of action!
可是我没有办法克服我的英雄主义
If only I could control my actions.
通常有英雄主义的人 都是身手好的人
A true man of action acts on instinct.
可是我也同意警队需要守纪律的人
I think the police force
不需要身手好的人
needs men with discipline.
身手好的人 才不会墨守成规
Instinctive men have to be unconventional,
虽然给人的印象是不守纪律
even at the cost of discipline.
身手不好的人呢 是不能不守纪律
If you did everything by the book, no case would ever get solved.
你说对不对
-Am I right?
对 这也是是事实
-Absolutely.
好了 我要上飞机了
I'd better get back on board.
哎呀 时间到了
You're right.
我走了 再见
Goodbye.
匪徒勒索多少钱
How much is the ransom?
1000万 没说怎么收钱
Ten million. That's all we know.
什么人干的
-Do we have any suspects?
一点头绪都没有啊
-Not a clue.
你说会不会是那些心理不正常的人干的
Do you think these people are insane?
你问我 那我问谁
Why are you asking me? I don't know.
有没有想过从炸弹来源方面着手呢
Have you traced the dynamite?
为什么要从炸弹来源着手
-Why?
为什么
-Yes, why?
很简单嘛
Simple.
香港的炸药贮存和使用都是受到管制的
Dynamite is a controlled substance.
用来做炸药的炸弹
You either smuggle it
要就是偷运进口
in or you steal it
要么就是从工业炸药方面得到的
from a local company.
对呀 我怎么没想到呢
He's right. We hadn't thought of that.
最好是在他们交赎款之前
We must find their bomb factory before
查到匪徒造炸弹和藏炸弹的地方
the company pays the ransom.
只要找到贼窝 他们就没戏唱了
If we do that, we can foil their plans.
为什么问题一到你手上
How is it you always
就这么容易解决呢
solve problems so easily?
你说这件案子不是你办谁来办呢
You're made for this case!
就是你了
You're
你去办吧
in charge.
Yes Sir
我要上飞机了
I've got a plane to catch.
家驹
Wait! Ka Kui.
家驹 巴厘岛不会沉的
Ka Kui.
什么时候去都行啊
You can go there anytime.
可是炸弹案一分钟都不能等啊
This case is once-in-a-lifetime.
- 我… - 下次再去吧
Go there next time. Okay?
那我也得跟阿美说一声
I'd better talk to May first.
那就快点去吧
Hurry up, then.
快点
Hurry up.
哎呀
Ooh!
小姐 飞机…
-Miss! -Yes, sir?
什么事啊
-My plane...
刚刚起飞
-It just took off.
飞走了
It's taken off!
怎么现在的飞机这么准时啊
Why is the plane so punctual now
阿美的护照还在我这儿呢
I still have May's passport!
糟了
Damn!
这下麻烦可大了
It sure isn't your lucky day!
现在怎么办
Now what?
骠叔 你好了没有
Uncle Bill, we'd better go.
好了
go.
怎么了
-You all right?
不知道吃错什么了
-I ate something bad.
走吧
go.
那边
-That way, sir.
- 谢谢 - 谢谢你啊
-Thank you.
小姐 我们是重案组的 约了王秘书
Excuse me. We're police officers. We're here to see Mr. Fung.
请你们上三十楼
-30th floor.
谢谢
-Thank you.
窃听器
Bugging devices.
非法偷听
A bug? Look out...
美国总统就是这样下台的
Nixon lost his job because of these.
你想不想破案
If we want to solve the case,
这叫知己知彼 百战百胜
we have to know our targets well.
看你的了
We're counting on you.
收起来
Put them away.
王秘书 有两位刑警 现在他们上来找你
Miss Wong, there are two police officers here.
请问洗手间在哪里
-Where's the bathroom?
直走右转
-On your right.
谢谢
Thanks.
谢谢你 二十五
Twenty-five, please.
麻烦你 二十四
Twenty-four, please.
请等一下
Wait!
骠叔
Uncle Bill,
我真担心阿美 不知道她现在怎么样了
I'm really worried about May.
我一回去 马上打电报到印尼机场
I'll  call Jakarta Airport as soon as I get back to the office.
骠叔
Uncle Bill.
你有没有公德心啊
You should be ashamed of yourself.
一点礼貌都没有
Haven't you got any manners?
我们搭另外一部
Let's use the others.
我是重案组刑警 约了王秘书 她知道
Detective Chan to see Miss Wong.
- 请你等一等 - 好的
-Please wait. -Thank you.
骠叔  家驹
-Ka Kui. -Uncle Bill.
这是训练你怎么背黑锅
I figured you were used to taking the blame.
你也用不着这样整人嘛
That's no excuse!
两位是…
Gentlemen.
我是张督察 他是陈队长
I'm Detective Chang. This is Detective Chan.
我们约了…
We...
陈Sir 张Sir 请跟我来
-Please come with me.
我们是…
-We're...
我知道 冯总裁正在开会
I know. Mr. Fung is busy now,
那份授权书已经准备好了
but he's signed the papers.
对不起啊
Excuse me.
请问你 洗手间在哪里
-Excuse me, where's the toilet?
直走左拐
-Down the corridor.
交给你
Here, sir.
谢谢
Thank you
对不起
I'm so sorry.
不好意思啊
没关系
It's okay.
你朋友呢
Where's your friend?
憋不住 唰一下就去了
He had a sudden urge.
那块地怎么样
How about that piece of land
总裁回来了
There's the chairman.
那块地要三亿以下买来才有赚
That site is worth three billion. There would be a profit.
好的  总裁
Yes, Mr. Chairman?
麻烦你了
Than ks for all your help.
谢谢你跟警方合作
You're developing the new properties very quickly.
大家请坐
Please sit.
各位董事 股东 各部门负责人
Directors, managers, and department heads, welcome.
今天开会的目的
I've called this meeting
是要跟大家检讨一下
to review the performance
过去半年地产的形势
of our property portfolio over the last six months,
然后制定新的一年销售的策略
and to set the sales target for the next year.
各位大概都注意到
You may all know that since
比起去年的最低点
the stock market collapse last year,
本港股市现在的价位
the Hang Seng Index
差不多回升到了股市暴跌以前的三分之二
has risen 66%.
现在我们来看看
Let me show you
本港今天有实力的股票趋势
the performance of
从今天的股票市场形势来看呢
the major blue chip shares.
酒店业和制作业的前途非常的好
The future of hotel industry and production industry is very good
连带香港其它的行业也受益不浅呢
However, given the performance of the bank and property sectors,
综合各银行股和地产业的表现
the outlook of the stock market for
今年下半年升和跌的机会似乎都会存在
the next six months remains uncertain.
在这种情形之下
In situations like this,
一般小投资者
small investors
还是会把资金投资在地产业上面
are likely to put their money in property.
各位
So
所以我看我们应该加速完成建设中的住宅区
we have to accelerate the pace of our new housing developments.
小姐 你好漂亮
Hi, gorgeous.
小姐
Miss.
总裁说 如果有人找衣服
If someone asks the chairman for this,
叫他拿500块来赎
it's$500 to get it back.
当然了 拜拜
Bye.
情况怎么样
-What happened?
进去开会啊
-It's a meeting.
窃听器装在会议室了没有
-Did you plant the bugs?
装了
-Sure.
办公室呢
-And the desk?
也装了
-All done.
他答应了
-Was it easy?
他没反对
-He wasn't against it!
他还说了些什么
-What did they say?
下半年买房子
-Something about houses.
买房子
Really?
你到哪儿去
-Where are you going?
我坐另外一部
-I'll take the next one.
家驹
Kai Kui
阿美啊
May's here.
阿美 你回来了
May, you're back!
阿美
May.
太过份了你
You scumbag!
阿美 你听我说嘛
Let me explain.
阿美…
You...
陈家驹 你是不是希望我回不来啊
you didn't want me to come back!
骗我上飞机 自己就跑了
You left me there and took my passport!
还把我护照拿走
When I got there,
害得我到了巴厘岛 玩也不能玩
I couldn't do anything.
就被人家送回香港来了
Before I was sent back here,
还扣留我十几个钟头
they detained me
当我是无证居民
for ten hours in a cell!
嘘 你嘘什么嘘
Why should
我死了也要说
I keep my voice down?
你带条狗上街 也不会不理它呀
When you take your dog for a walk,
你会不会把它扔在街上 不带它回家呀
do you not take him home afterwards?
我连狗都不如啊
I'm even worse than a dog!
阿美 你看你像什么样 人家在看你呀
May, they're watching us.
看什么看嘛
watching?
我又没有看你们
What are you staring at?
我跟他说话 关你们什么事嘛
This is none of your business!
- 阿美… - 说啊
May
你当着大家面告诉我
I want you to tell me
我在你心目中到底算什么
in front of everyone what you think I am!
你把我当什么 你说呀你
What the hell do you take me for?
女朋友 女朋友行了吧
You're my girlfriend!
女朋友
Your girlfriend?
你开门 开门呀你
Open up! Open up!
女朋友个屁 我是你女朋友
If that's true, why do you treat me this way?
你对一个普通市民也比对你女朋友好啊
You treat strangers better than me!
我郑重地告诉你
Let me tell you...
我们两个完了
...it's over between us!
陈家驹 我恨死你了
Chan Ka Kui, I hate you!
骠叔啊
Uncle Bill,
你有没有帮我打电报啊
did you make that call?
我打算大完便再给你打嘛
I had to go to the toilet.
我被你害死了
You killed me
不要你那么好心
Don't be so kind
你走开 我撞死你啊
You've ruined my life!
阿美…
May
走开
-Go away!
你不要这么犟嘛
-Don't be childish!
别拉我的包 走开
Don't grab my bag! Go away!
不要碰我 走开 走远一点…
Don't even touch me. Go away. Leave me alone.
阿美 我有话要跟你说
Let me explain.
我没话跟你说
I don't want to know.
要说的话已经说完了
I've nothing else to say to you.
- 我这辈子不想见到你 - 阿美…
May!
阿美 你没事吧
May, are you all right?
你走开
Stay away from me.
- 你走开 不要碰我 - 阿美…
Stay away from me. Don't touch my motorbike.
你走开 你不要碰我车子
Keep away. I don't want you anywhere near me.
阿美…
May
- 你走开啊 - 听我解释嘛…
-Let me explain. -Keep away.
还不过来帮忙
Why won't you help me?
你走开 我再也不要见到你了
阿美
Just keep away from me. I never want to see you again.
May.
有什么好看的 快去做事情去
All right, get back to work. I want to see Ka Kui.
叫家驹进来
Ka Kui, the boss wants to see you.
- 家驹 叫你哪 - 叫你哪
Ka Kui,
Sorry Sir
完了…对不起
I'm sorry, sir.
要不要帮你给阿美打电话解释一下
Would you like to call may for an explanation
现在解释也没用了
I don't think it would help.
不用解释了
Don't explain anything to women!
我跟我老婆也这么说
This is my way to handle ¡®em...
男人出去就是做事
if a man's not at home,
回家就是做完了
it's obvious he's working.
对不对
Excuse me,
对不起 我又要去厕所了
I have to go to the toilet.
别学骠叔的大男人主义
Don't pay any attention to his chauvinism.
快去换件衣服吧
Go and get changed.
Sorry Sir
阿美…
May...
你走了
You are go...
坐一整天都没话说
It's better than wasting my time here.
我走了
Good night.
那我送你回家好了
Can I walk you home?
不用了
No thanks.
你不要乱来啊
Don't be foolish!
我没有乱来
I won't.
不关她的事 你找我
Get me, it's me you want.
千万不要乱来
Don't be foolish.
跟你们两个统统有关
-You're in this together.
你有话慢慢说
-Don't try anything.
我要打死你
Prepare to die!
阿美
May
吓死你们了吧
I really had you going!
我要整死你
I got the both of you!
家驹
Ka Kui!
枪在这儿
I've found it.
勇探
Brove
两三下就清洁溜溜了
Looks like you're outnumbered.
早知道这么容易就摆平了
If I thought it was just a simple game,
我也不用找那么多人来收拾你了
I wouldn't call my men to come.
是我老板看得起你
My boss thinks highly of you
他说要整死你
I'm getting paid to do it.
那我拿了人家的钱 就要替他消灾了
Then  I'll  take the money and help him
又不用我动手
But I don't need
我说句话 自然有人收拾你了
to dirty my hands.
我们可不是冷血动物啊
My men can take care of you.
只要你肯向我们大哥求饶的话
If you apologise to Mr. Ko now,
我们就给你打个对折
we won't break both of your legs.
用一条腿就算了
We'll just break one of them.
别想了
Cut the bullshit.
有种开枪啊
Go on, kill me.
杀警察的罪 那可大啰
Kill a cop? I don't think so.
我老板只说要整你
My boss wants to teach you a lesson.
我看 断手断脚也行吧
Ripping a few limbs off should do the trick.
动手
Get him!
追
Go!
他在这 打断他的腿 打断他的腿啊
There he is. Beat him up!
给我打 把他打残废了
Go on, finish him off. Get up.
起来 过去
Move over.
我来开
Let me drive.
我撞你个王八蛋
I'll  turn you into mashed banana.
不关我的事啊 我也是拿人钱的
It wasn't my fault! I was paid to do it.
你别过来啊 我不跟你玩了
Keep away or  I'll  shoot!
我打死你啊
Shoot me!
有种你开枪啊
-I'll shoot.
我开枪了啊
-Shoot here!
把我打死
Shoot here!
我真的开枪了
It's not my fault.
我开…
-Shoot
不关我的事 不关我的事啊…
It's not. It's not my fault.
下次再惹我 我要你命
Next time I'll kick your ass. It's not my fault!
阿美
May
阿美 你没事吧
May. Did they hurt you?
我没事
I'm all right.
你小心你自己
You'd better be careful.
你为什么还要去追呢
Why did you chase him?
多危险
That's dangerous.
我只是想帮你出口气
I wanted to make things up to you.
如果刚才射的不是墨水
If it had been acid in that pistol
是硝镪水
and not ink...
出什么气都没用
I'd be scarred for life.
也许 他只是想引开你来对付我
Maybe they wanted to distract you and then kidnap me.
那我怎么办
Then what would happen?
家驹
Ka Kui,
我希望我男朋友温柔体贴
I want my boyfriend to be gentle,
不是好勇斗狠
not a savage.
懂了吗
Do you understand?
进来
Come in.
早上好 Sir
Mornning Sir.
现役探员在公园殴斗
"Police Detective in Park Rumpus."
这个人是谁啊
Who was that?
你看看
Look!
我出去看看小狗队
I'll check out the surveillance team.
ACTIVE-DUTY POLICEMAN INVOLVED IN 10-MAN PARK BRAWL
是我 Sir
It was me.
Sorry Sir
Sorry, sir.
如果是朱滔那帮人来报仇
I know Chu wants revenge,
你不应该当私人恩怨来处理
but don't take the law into your own hands.
对不起
Sorry, sir.
要不要我帮忙
Anything I can do?
不用了
No, thanks.
我想那帮人是虚张声势
I can cope with it.
我不愿意再把这件事情扩大
I just want them to leave me alone.
总之 凡事要小心一点
All right. But keep your eyes open.
上面派了小狗队来帮你忙
Now we've got a surveillance team.
他们蛮能干的
They're very good.
去跟他们聊聊吧
Go and talk to them.
Thank you Sir
他有没有骂你啊
Did he give you an earful?
他一定…
Did he...?
到那边去
Let's go over there.
幸亏我走得快 救你一命啊
He just wants to help.
他骂人的时候没有观众 他怎么骂嘛
How can somebody show off if they don't have an audience?
张Sir
Sir!
这位是陈家驹警官
This is officer Chen Jiaju
吴警员 梅警员
Officer Wu, officer Mei
大家自我介绍
Let's introduce ourselves
自我介绍…
introduce oneself to
他们几个是特种部队的小狗队
This is the Special Tactical Unit.
请坐
Please take a seat.
他们最擅长跟踪
They have great expertise in tracking targets.
你们认为跟踪对这件案子有用吗
But why? Will this be useful for the case?
因为现在连什么人干的都不知道
Because we don't even know who did it.
只要跟踪可疑人物 就知道什么人干的了
Just follow the suspect and you'll know who did it
就可以找到制造炸弹和藏炸弹的地方
You can find the place where the bombs are made and hidden
只要跟踪匪徒
We could follow them
就可以在他们收赎款的时候把他们逮捕
during the transaction, then arrest them.
就这么简单
-That simple?
是这么简单了
-Of course.
好 我就是喜欢你们充满信心
Good. That's why I always have faith in you.
希望你们合作愉快
Hope you have a smooth collaboration.
吴警员 我有事要跟你谈谈
Detective Ng, could I have a word with you?
你们快有办公室了
There will be room for you soon.
- 拜拜 - 拜拜
bye
陈警官
-Detective Chan. -Yes.
你摇头是什么意思
What does that mean?
我摇头是说…
It's mean
你们一级棒
You guys are cool.
冯总裁说 他的股票会升到八块多
President Feng said his stock would rise to more than eight yuan
知道了也没钱买
That's hardly relevant.
还有啊
And
刚选出来的沙滩小姐是他女朋友
his girlfriend is a supermodel!
三八 你好好听吧
I'm not interested.
我来帮你听 你打个电话给阿美
I'll take it. You go and call May.
去啊
Go on.
家驹 有消息了
Ka Kui! Listen!
我已经把这件事向董事局报告过了
Your conditions have been presented to the board,
原则上他们同意付钱
and they have agreed to pay.
别说那么多废话
No shit.
钱准备好了没有
Do you have the money?
准备得差不多了
We don't have it all.
你知道1000万可不是小数目啊
$10 million is a lot of money.
查电话来源
Trace it.
追踪
大浦汀角路
He's on Ting Kok Road.
总部呼叫
HQ, calling all foot patrols.
大埔汀角路有没有警员
OVER
over?
大埔汀角路有没有兄弟在 OVER
Are there any units on Ting Kok Road, over?
有啊 我是PC12674 什么事 OVER
This is PC 12674 on Ting Kok Road, over.
PC12674听着
PC 12674,
查清楚电话亭里出来的人的身份 OVER
check anybody leaving a phone box in the area.
知道了
Copy
你报了警 想拖延时间
Are you stalling for time?
没有 没报警啊
No, we didn't call the police.
我们不会乱来的
we didn't
我现在要2000万
Now we want 20 million.
2000万
Twenty million!
这个数目…
Such a huge sum.
别讨价还价
Find it.
喂 喂喂…
Wait!
PC12674
This is PC 12674.
我已经发现可疑人物
We found...
你要小心 这个人是危险人物
Be careful. He's very dangerous.
身上可能有武器
He could be armed.
千万不要打草惊蛇
Keep everything low key.
知道了
Copy that.
哎 先生
Excuse me.
有斑马线你不走 这样不对 你知道吗
You're supposed to use the pedestrian crossing.
你开车吧
-Move along.
原谅我一次吧
-Give me a chance, Officer.
身份证拿出来
Can I see your ID card?
呼叫总台
Calling HQ...
PC 12674
PC 12674, do you copy?
注意 大埔汀角路电话亭需要援助
An officer needs assistance
附近的警员立刻去支援
on Ting Kok Road.
对不起 这里面没他照片
I'm sorry, he isn't here.
有什么好对不起的
Don't be sorry.
一个警员被人抢了枪嘛
That's the way things go.
又没做错事
It wasn't your fault.
你当警察多久了
How long have you been in uniform?
刚从警校出来 两个月了
About two months.
那就更值得原谅了
Then you're excused.
不过 枪被人抢了 很吃亏啊
Will I get in trouble for
不一定啊
losing my gun?
起码你的经验就比他们多一点
As long as you learn from the experience, it's okay.
要是当个警察 枪都没有被人抢过
-It happens to every cop.
那多没面子
That's...
我以后会注意点了
-It won't happen again.
再看到他 你认得他吗
Do you think you'd recognise him?
化成灰我也认得
Sure.
陈Sir 电话
Phone.
加入我们这组 一起做吧
I could do with someone like you on the team.
我去跟上面说
I'll  see to it.
好
Yes.
谢谢
Thank you.
帮我把档案拿过去
Can you file this for me?
好
Yes.
哪位
-Hello.
百搭
-It's Joker.
说
-Go ahead.
有消息了
-News.
什么消息
What news?
有个人叫石辉 专卖炸药的
A guy called Crazy Fai sells dynamite.
今天晚上9点 海王酒吧见
Nine o'clock, Hoi Wong Bar.
你知道怎么做了吧
-Do you know what we'll do next? -No.
我才不知道呢
Really?
不知道
I don't know.
哎 老兄
-What do you want?
辉哥 我有点事想跟你谈
-Are you Fai?
一次生 两次熟嘛
I want to talk.
好吧 我们到那边谈
All right. Let's go over there.
你慢慢吃
I'll  be right back.
请问贵姓
-What's your name?
我叫罗初六
-Lo.
有什么指教
What do you want?
我想跟你买鱼炮
Some explosives.
辉哥 朋友介绍我来的
My friend introduced me
买鱼炮干什么
-What are they for?
抓鱼啰
-Fishing.
你的长相不像水生
You don't look like a fisherman.
难道我拿鱼炮去做大买卖呀
What if I told you it was for business?
有好处
I'll  give you a good price.
反正事成之后 少不了你的
What do you say?
可以考虑考虑
All right..,
我帮你问问
but I need to speak to someone.
不过货不是我的
It's not my stuff.
你等等
Don't go away.
谢谢
Thanks.
不好意思 我朋友早就不做了
Sorry, he's out of stock,
他可以帮你问问
but he'll call me back.
你坐会儿
Stay here,
我跟女朋友吃完东西就过来
I'll  be back when I've finished.
- 好 - 你等等
Thank you.
老兄 站起来
Hey, you. Stand up.
CID啊
CID
站起来
Stand Up
过去
Go over
站好
Stand Up
搜搜他
Search him
老兄 我是来喝酒的
Man, I'm here for a drink
什么喝酒
a drink?
有人打电话 说你藏有违禁品
We heard you were dealing contraband.
看什么
Eyes front.
别动
Hold it!
连枪带套 一起扔给我
Throw me your gun. Quick!
快点 站过去
Stand over there.
老兄
Easy.
千万别乱来啊
Don't do anything stupid.
起来…
Come on.
在不在你身上
Move.
出来 出来
Come out!
走开
Get lost.
岂有此理 王八蛋
You screwed me over, you bastard!
你可以不卖给我货
Why did you call the cops?
救命啊 救命啊 救命啊
Stop! Stop it!
老大 别打了 再打我就没命了
Please, that's enough.
我怎么知道你是不是条子
Please stop.
所以找两个CID来试试你
That's why I called the cops,
要货简单嘛
to prove it.
你有没有钱
I can get what you need.
有钱就有货嘛
It's cash on delivery.
你把风
Keep a lookout.
威力大不大
Is it good stuff?
炸石头的 你说大不大
It's from the quarries.
有 还有很多
Yes.
我这里的货
There's enough
整栋帝国大厦都可以炸掉
to blow up the Empire State Building.
我不认识他
I don't know him
我第一次见他
I just met him!
我真的不认识他
I've never seen him before!
不关我的事啊
Not my businese
你猜你跑得掉吗
Do you think you can get away?
喝咖啡
Would you like some coffee?
抽烟
A cigarette?
够
OK
冷气是不是太冷了
The temperature okay?
不冷 很舒服嘛
Fine.
这样录口供 我是他 才不理你呢
This is stretching the law. If I were him, I'd clam up.
既然这么舒服 应该跟我们合作了
You seem comfortable. Will you cooperate with us now?
跟你合作
Cooperate?
你合作 我们也合作
我们会替你保守秘密
We'llkeep everything secret.
必要时 会派人保护你
If need be, we'll keep you under protection.
如果有你们三个保护我一辈子呢
If you three could protect me the rest of my life,
也许我会考虑一下
then I would consider it.
你不要说得这么轻松
Don't talk that way.
就算我们放你走啊
Even if we were to release you now,
你一出门口呢
we might,
我们就找个人在你身上搜出几包白粉
say, "find" drugs on you after you were gone,
或者找个未成年少女告你强奸也行啊
or maybe "discover" you've been molesting young girls.
你们用这个方法 他会招供吗
Does this get you good results?
从来没失败过
Sure. It never fails.
算了 算了
Never mine
你们想陷害我什么 尽管来吧
What's the charge?
老子什么场面没见过
I've seen a lot worse than this.
不过我倒想跟你们玩玩
I'll play along before I'll go to jail.
用不着说翻脸就翻脸嘛 对不对
You all seem like nice young ladies!
没见过女人打人吗
Have you not seen anything like this before?
不要打了 不要打了…
No! Stop! I've had enough.
小姐 不要打了…
No, please!
不要打了…
Nice young ladies, huh?
是你说要跟我玩的
Aren't you going to play along?
我一定告你们这些臭女人
I'll  sue you!
还敢嘴硬
Say that again.
当心我一枪打死你
Guns have a way of going off when you least expect it.
我就说是枪走火
We'lljust say it
你这种人 死了也没人可怜
was an accident.
我说了 我说了…
No! I'll talk.
早说不就没事了嘛
Why didn't you say so?
就是啊
-Cigarette? -No.
来来来 来…
Come on,
坐 来 痛不痛啊
sit down.
有人看你啊
There are men in here.
没见过啊
Show's over.
我最近卖过炸药给几个人
I have sold three explosives lately.
一个叫阿胜的
One buyer named Xing, he was a fisherman.
是个水上人
I've known him a long time.
他说买给水上人炸鱼用
He bought it to blast reef fish.
一个叫军火刘
The other guy buys my stuff
听说他专门捡空的弹壳
to refill empty bullet shell cases
买炸药回去 自己做子弹
so he can sell them.
然后再卖出去
But he's only bought a few.
还有一个叫北极熊的
The third guy's
他买的最多
name was Polar Bear.
可能要做一笔大买卖
He's a big-time dealer.
平常他多数在油麻地的弹子房出出进进
He usually hangs out at the Yaumatei Pool Hall.
Taxi
Taxi.
目标上了计程车
Target's in a taxi.
车牌DP5608
It's DP5608.
大口 收到了吗
Got it, Big Mouth?
车牌DP5608
Taxi number DP5608,
现在向爵士道北行
heading north to Kok Road.
大口收到
Copy, Big Mouth. I see target DP5608.
目标在地铁站下车
It's headed to TST Metro Station.
小狗队出动
All copy. All copy.
目标在地铁站下车
Renew info. Get to TST Metro Station.
目标在地铁站
Target on metro heading to Kung Tong.
知道了
Roger.
你留在车里监视
-Stay there. -Yes.
目标已经下车了
Target off metro.
目标上了计程车
Target in taxi CW721,
车牌是CW721
向工业区方向行驶
heading to industrial area.
目标已经下了车 转入日升街
Target out of the car, heading to Yat Sing Street.
OVER
Copy.
收到 OVER 阿蕊 你先归队
Over. Sun, your team leaves first.
流动监视车立刻到日升街 展开监视
Car to Yat Sing Street. Start supervision.
听候命令
Wait for orders.
收到了 OVER
Yes.
我去看看
I'll take a look.
先生 请问百乐街在哪儿
Hey, buddy, where is Pak Lok Street?
不知道
-No idea.
谢谢
-Thanks.
抢我枪那个人 拿着两包东西向你那儿去了
Someone carrying two bags heading your way.
阿豪
Polar Bear.
买东西啊
You went shopping?
有没有被人盯上
Were you followed?
我可没有 你有没有
No. Don't worry.
别看了 开门
Come on. Open up.
有三个人
There are three of them.
陈Sir
Detective Chan,
他跟另外一个人进了个货仓
it's him.
里面还有一个人在等他们
These must be the guys.
怎么样
What's it...
陈Sir 里面有三个人
Three voices.
在这等着
Louder, let me hear it.
继续监视
我们已经到了
Find a place at the TST. Make sure everything is fine.
他们出来了
Three people.
大家要小心 他们已经出来了
-They're coming out.
收到了
-Roger.
便宜你了
-You don't deserve this.
-You don't!
找人查他们的车牌
Check the plates
488跟踪他们
and follow the van.
你留在这儿 我下去看看
You stay here. I'll go and take a look.
Yes Sir
你们收拾东西 我下去看看
Right. Let's go.
488开车了
他们停车了
We're starting the car.
上车
Come in car
488跟丢了
Yes.
家驹 去哪儿
-Where are you going?
我进去看看
-To take a look.
小心点
-Be careful.
知道了
-I will.
收到
I see.
陈Sir
Detective Chan,
那些混蛋耍花招 488跟丢了
they've shaken off our unit.
没关系 他们一定会回来的
Don't worry, they'll come back.
叫他们归队吧
Call them off.
Yes Sir
488归队
Come back here.
不要 是我
Don't shoot! It's me!
不要吵
Be quiet.
被你吓死了
You scared me.
拌了一跤
-I fell over.
还有人
-Someone's up there.
- 别动 - 别动
Hold it!
转过去
Turn around.
我们是警察
Police!
你在干什么
Who are you?
他可能又聋又哑
This guy must be deaf.
你看没看到 刚刚有三个人在这里头啊
Did you see three men come through here a few hours ago?
交给你了
You ask him.
你在这儿做什么的
Do you work here?
你在这儿睡觉啊
Do you sleep here?
喂 我可是没辙了
Right. I can't communicate with him.
他又上天又下水的
I got an answer, but I have no idea what it means.
搞不懂他干嘛
You ask him.
你来问他吧
Take him down
带回警察局
to the station.
来吧
It's okay.
我只是带你回去问话
You're coming with me for questioning.
不痛的 真的不痛
Come along. It won't cost anything.
不用拷了
No need for cuffs.
这些东西是干什么用的
Why do you collect such things?
忘了他是个聋子
He's deaf.
这里所有的东西都是你的吗
Are all these toys in here yours?
别走
-Freeze!
他又听不到 快追
-He can't hear you!
快把枪找回来
After him!
陈Sir 什么事啊 陈Sir
Sir! Are you all right?
什么事啊
Are you all right?
大家分头找一个人
There's a deaf-mute running around.
他是哑巴 小心点
Find him.
Yes Sir
Yes, sir!
走…
Go.
没想到那个哑巴真厉害
I didn't know he could fight.
我也没想到
Neither did I.
快点把枪给找回来吧
Go and find my gun.
好
Okay.
如果收购印度洋银行的计划
If we can manage to finance the buyout of Indian Ocean Bank,
能够顺利进行的话
it would be
那我们向股东集资的理由
a welcome addition
就更充分了
to our portfolio.
冯总裁 电话
Mr. Fung, telephone.
告诉过你 我不接电话嘛
I said no calls.
又是上次那个人打来
I know, but it's that man again.
噢
Ooh!
去听电话
Jimmy.
对不起啊
Excuse me.
你骗我们 你报警了
You called the cops.
我 我想你误会了 我们根本没有…
No, you must be mistaken. We haven't!
不用再装了
You needn't try and deceive us.
我早料到你们会报警的
We knew you'd go to the cops.
为了让你们死了这条心
To make you abandon that idea,
明天中午十二点
we will demonstrate our power to you tomorrow at 12:00.
如果你们认为值得给这2000万呢
We won't waste time bargaining with you ever again.
就在后天早上
After 12:00 tomorrow, if you decide it's prudent to pay the$20 million,
用你置业集团的名义
place an ad in the name of your Zhiye Group
在一份畅销的报纸上
in one of the major newspapers
登一段广告
the day after tomorrow.
通知署长
Call Mr. Lam!
明天中午十二点
After 12:00 tomorrow,
如果你们认为值得给这2000万呢
if you decide it's prudent to pay the$20 million,
就在后天早上
place an ad in the name
用你置业集团的名义
of your Zhiye Group
在一份畅销的报纸上
in one of the major newspapers
登一段广告
the day after tomorrow.
哪里打出来的
Where?
可能是一个改装过的无线电话打出的
It was a modified mobile phone,
所以查不到
so we couldn't trace it.
我早料到你们会报警
We knew you'd go to the cops.
为了让你们死了这条心
To make you abandon that idea,
我们会在明天十二点
we will demonstrate our power
证明给你们看我们的威力
to you tomorrow at 12:00.
现在开始
Now.
我不会再浪费时间 讨价还价
We won't waste time bargaining with you ever again.
放心吧 他们吓唬人的
Don't worry, they're bluffing.
我们已经加派人手
We've sent extra officers
在你名下的产业戒备
to protect your buildings.
没事的
You'll be fine.
绝不能让他们这么猖狂
They must not be allowed to be so rampant
说炸就炸
Just blow it up
Yes Sir
Yes, sir!
阿辉
Fay!
好久不见
Long time no see.
熊哥
Polar Bear.
这是坚哥 握个手吧
This is Ken. H&d like a word with you.
我真的没有把你们供出来
I didn't snitch on you!
你没供
Really?
你被抓之后 条子就上门了
Then why did they turn up after you got caught?
没招供 条子为什么把你放出来
And why did they let you go so quickly?
他们证据不足 准我保释而已啊
Lack of evidence. They granted me bail.
我真的没有招供啊
I didn't snitch,
招不招都无所谓
I swear!
我们敢做 就不怕你说
It's all the same to us. We don't care.
带我去哪儿
-Where are we going?
用不着你管
-Make any difference?
王秘书
-Miss Wong.
早
-Yes?
信件刚才已经检查过了
-We've checked the mail.
谢谢
-Thanks.
王秘书 有人送花给你
And these are for you.
不知道 是个男人送来的
I don't know.
他放下就走了
If you don't know, who would?
谢谢你
Thanks.
把这东西放在一个地方
Plant this bomb
旧账就一笔勾销
and we're even.
没第二条路 抱紧点吧
Do the job or you're finished.
那放在哪里啊
-Where shall I put it?
到时候就知道了
-I'll tell you later.
开车
Let's go.
收到了 继续戒备
Roger. Thanks a lot. Keep an eye out.
大家小心点
Ready.
CID
I'm a cop.
- 怎么样 - 没东西
-What? -Nothing.
没有
Nothing.
我是CID 检查你的袋子
CID. Your case.
干嘛啊
What?
已经有人到了
Nothing.
我现在查
Okay.
CID 打开看看
What's that?
知道了
Excuse me.
CID
CID.
是不是神经病啊
May I see your bag?
CID
快点回来
Make it quick.
应该没问题
-It should be fine.
冯总裁 信检查过了
-Here's the mail, sir.
收到了
Roger.
会不会是唬人的
Do you think it's a bluff?
小心点好
I hope so,
宁可信其有 不可信其无
but we can't be sure.
知道了 保持联络
Okay. Keep in touch.
喂
Yes?
你让他等一等
Ask her to wait a minute.
收到了
Roger.
家驹
Ka Kui,
阿美在楼下说有要紧事
May's downstairs.
让你下去一下
She wants to talk to you urgently.
谢谢
Thanks.
阿美
May.
什么事啊
What's the matter?
这封信给你
I've written a letter for you.
我走了
Goodbye.
阿美
May.
你急着找我 就是要给我这封信
You came all this way to give me this?
很重要 你收起来吧
It's important, so keep it safe.
拜
Bye.
你摩托车呢
Oh, yeah, where's the scooter?
摩托车跟我们两个都合不来 我卖了
We didn't get along, so I sold it.
我跟那女的
I'll follow her.
我已经加派人手 全都布置好了
I have my backup units in position.
放心吧 他们吓唬人的
Yes. I think they're bluffing.
我们全靠警方了
Then we should depend on the police.
好
All right.
怎么回事啊
What is going on?
打电话叫救护车 快
Call an ambulance. Come on
给我打电话找署长
Call Mr. Lam.
怎么会这样
How did this happen? -Go and investigate.
大家冷静点 家驹 我们下去
-Stay calm. Don't panic. Ka Kui, come with me.
快点 快去看看
Call the fire department. Come on!
救火 快…救火
Bring a fire extinguisher.
快点帮忙救火
Come on. Put the fire out first.
拿灭火筒
Come on, get moving.
- 救火车来了没有 - 没有
-Is the ambulance here? -No.
快点打电话给消防车
Call the fire engine quickly
快…帮忙救火 快点
Go call them!
灭火筒 快点
Fire extinguisher, come on
消防车来了没有 快 帮忙救火
Did the fire engine come to help put out the fire
署长 冯总裁打电话来
We need more help.
骠叔 我上去一下
-Phone, sir. -Bill, you take the phone call.
家驹 我上去听电话 你马上来
Ka Kui, meet me upstairs.
你们警察怎么做事的
I thought you were supposed to protect me.
总裁秘书被人炸断了一只手
The president's secretary was blown off his hand
THE ZHIYE GROUP, TOGETHER WITH EVERY HONG KONG CITIZEN,
STRIVES TO PRESERVE THE BEAUTY OF HONG KONG
这位秘书现在怎么样
-How's Miss Wong?
手术很好
-She's doing well.
医生说
她的手恢复的机会有百分之九十五
The doctor said her arm would recover.
她脸上的伤
They'll do
拿大腿的肉来补
a skin graft on her face later.
过一阵子才知道结果
So we'll wait and see.
人家现在已经决定给钱了
Wong's decided to pay up.
我怎么跟署长交代
What am I going to tell Raymond?
骠叔
Uncle Bill, that's the way it goes.
我们也不希望这样
We always said it was going
做任何事都有挫折
to be a tough case.
你不要忘了
We're dealing
我们这次对付的 是真正的悍匪
with well-organised criminals here.
我宁愿他炸我
I wish they'd blown me up instead.
我痛嘛 不用大家这么难过
I don't like putting lives at risk.
不过你放心 我们已经布置好了
But don't worry.
只要他一收赎款 我们就会抓住他
If they come to collect the money, I'm sure we'll get them.
如果我这样跟署长说
If I pass on what you said to Raymond,
他一定会说我没有实际行动
he won't be happy at all.
还说这些冠冕堂皇的话干什么
What we need is real action.
Sir
Sir!
人家决定给钱了
I guess you've seen the papers.
这件事你叫我跟上面怎么交代
Now what do I tell the Chief?
还有什么好说的
That's the way it goes.
谁愿意这样
We always said
做什么事都会有挫折
it'd be a tough case.
不要忘了 我们这次要对付的
We're dealing
是一群真正的悍匪
with well-organised criminals here.
我宁愿他炸我
I wish they'd blown me up instead.
我痛嘛 不用大家现在心情这么难过
I don't like putting lives at risk.
不过你放心
But don't worry.
我们已经布置好了
If they come to collect the money,
如果他们一收钱 我立刻抓他
I'm sure we'll get them.
一点实际行动都没有
All this is talk.
说些冠冕堂皇的话干嘛
What we need is some real action.
这下糟糕了
Something's up.
署长惨了
Raymond's in trouble.
谁都不希望发生这种事
That's the way it goes.
其实做事难免会遇到挫折
We always said it'd be a tough case.
不过大家不要忘了
We're dealing
我们这次面对的是一群真正的悍匪
with well-organised criminals here.
我宁愿炸的是我
I wish they'd blown me up instead.
我痛嘛 不用大家难过
I don't like putting lives at risk.
不过请放心
But don't worry.
我保证 只要他们敢收钱 我立刻抓人
If they come to collect, I'm sure we'll get them.
我完全明白你所遭遇的困难
I understand your situation,
我会照你的话 跟上面说的
and  I'll  note it in the report.
你放心好了
Good luck with the case.
祝你能够早日破案
You come, too.
这几天怎么了 闷闷不乐的
Why the long face?
又跟家驹吵架 是不是啊
Did you two have a fight?
不会了 以后再也…
Right. But this is the last one. Yes?
你等等啊
I'll  get him!
拿着
Hold this.
家驹 有紧急电话
Ka Kui, telephone.
接进来
Put it through.
是 接进去
Right. Put it through.
- 家驹啊 - 是啊
-Hello? -Ka Kui.
阿美被人抓走了
May's been kidnapped!
什么时候
When?
刚才我们从超级市场出来
We'd just left the shop
阿美就被两个男人抓上车去了
when someone dragged her into a van.
你知不知道他们是什么人
Who did it?
不知道
I don't know.
喂 一定又是你惹回来的仇人
But it must have something to do with you.
对了 是不是上次那个混蛋
Could it be those thugs again?
Yes Sir
朱滔
Chu Tu.
家驹啊 喂… 家驹啊
Ka Kui! Hello?
哎呀 你不知道了
家驹 什么事
-Ka Kui! What's up?
- 什么 - 我去找那个混蛋
-An old score. May's been kidnapped!
家驹
Ka Kui!
- 他怎么了 - 没说就走了
-What happened? -May's been kidnapped.
你别装死啊
What's the matter?
签完这张支票 给我再死啊
Sign this cheque before you're dead.
我那帮兄弟…
Our brothers...
- 他是病人… - 你让我把话说完呢  先生 你别这样了
-Please stop. He's a patient. -Let me finish.
我们那些兄弟帮你打死打活的
We did what you asked.
没有功劳 也有苦劳啊
That's why we deserve something.
你想抱钱进棺材啊
You won't need any money when you're dead.
朱滔
Chu Tu!
-Chu Tu!
你…
-Hey, you!
朱滔
Chu Tu!
你把阿美交出来
Bring May back!
我不知道 是他
I know nothing!
我什么都没做过 是他呀
I did nothing! It's him! Him!
你快把阿美还给我
Bring May back!
先生 你不可以这样对病人呢
Sir, you can't do that to a patient! Stop it!
放手啊
Put him down!
说 你把她藏在哪儿了
Speak up! What have you done with May?
不 不是我做的
-I didn't take her.
现在我有病 又没钱
-Who did, then?
谁还有空对付你啊
What reason would I have for taking her?
是啊 有钱也要留着治病啊
If he did have any money, he'd be pouring it into treatment.
这件事与我无关
This is none of our doing.
以前所有的事 全是他指使的
Hassling you was business, not personal.
我是看钱的份上才做的
We only did it on account of the money.
那会是谁呢
Then who could it be?
那边有电话 你回电话吧
There's a phone over there.
老家伙 你别死 你签完支票再死啊
Don't die before you sign this!
以后别再惹我
You! I've had about enough of you!
他都死了 我才懒得理你呢
He's got one foot in the grave,
如果他没死 也许会吧
so what do I care?
哪位Call1478
-Hello, this is 1378.
家驹
-Ka Kui!
阿美 阿美啊
May!
认得女朋友的声音吧
You recognise her voice.
立刻来新发路鸿丰工厂大厦
We're at the Hung Fung Industrial Building.
你们是什么人 到底想干什么
Who is this?
你一个人来吧
What do you want?
不然你得帮你女朋友收尸了
Come alone or she's dead.
喂…
Hello? Hello?
新发路
I know where that is.
阿美
May!
你没事吧
Are you all right?
你别乱叫
Be quiet.
你怎么样了
Are you all right?
我没事
I'm okay.
你们抓她干什么
Why have you kidnapped her?
家驹 当你看到这封信的时候…
"Ka Kui, by the time you read this letter..."
你不要念了
Stop!
我已经决定离开你…
"...I've decided we should be apart."
我求你 不要念了
No.
以后再也不见你了
"I don't think  I'll  see you again."
情书哎
It's a love letter!
要分手了
Just like they say...
亲爱的 再见
unlucky in love, lucky in money. There's more.
你们这些混蛋
Bastard!
当初 我觉得你热爱工作
"When we first met, I thought you liked your job very much,
是个可以终身依靠的男人
"and you'd be my Mr. Right.
现在我不能忍受
"Now I realise the only thing
你爱你的工作比爱我更多
that matters in your life is your work.
我问自己
"I tell myself
为什么当初喜欢你的原因
what made me fall in love with you
现在会变成我要离开你的理由
"is also what makes me want to leave you."
对啊
Yeah,
好好的 为什么要分手啊
why? Why did you break up?
你说
"You told me
你当警察惹来太多个仇人
you didn't want me involved
怕会连累我
with your work,
但是我不介意
"but I didn't mind.
我只介意 你没时间陪我
"What I did mind, though, is that you never spent enough time with me.
跟你在一起 是世界上最快乐的事
"Being with you was the happiest time of my life.
但怕梦见你 而你又不在
"But when you weren't there,
那会变成世界上最难忍受的痛苦
it was the worst time of my life."
就是说 如果我不离开你的话
"I'd spend my life
我一辈子都要忍受梦不到你的痛苦
waiting for you to come home!"
你们不要再念了
Can't you stop it?
她哭了…
She's crying!
他也哭了
So is he.
继续 继续呀
Keep reading,
是呀 快点…
go on.
因为 你是一个永不休息的警察
"...because you can never stop being a policeman."
永不休息的警察
A policeman who never stops.
那我们不惨了
We're in trouble.
离开你只是痛苦一次
"I think it's the right decision.
请原谅我作这个自私的选择
"Please forgive me for making such a selfish choice.
美
May."
我们不想干嘛
What don't we want
要你帮我们发财
I want you to help us get rich
你也知道 置业集团被人勒索
You must have heard the Zhiye Group was blackmailed.
勒索最难就是收钱了
The hardest part of the job is the pick-up.
所以要你帮我们收
You'll collect the ransom for us.
你们别做梦了
No way!
有你选择的余地吗
You don't have a choice.
哑巴 他说不干呢
He said no.
让他尝尝掌心雷
I think you'll enjoy this.
住手啊
Stop!
不要…
Don't!
我求求你们
Stop it! Please!
住手…
Stop it! Please stop it!
家驹 要不要紧啊
Ka Kui, are you hurt?
我没事
Don't worry.
死到临头还嘴硬
So you want to play the hero?
马上就轮到你了
Now it's your turn.
你想干嘛
What's you want?
住手啊
Please don't!
把车放正
Stop the car.
王八蛋
You rotten swine!
哑巴 了不起
Nice one!
有种杀了我
Kill me if you've got the guts.
你还真能挨呀
So tough!
是吗
Really?
我看看他马子能不能挨
Let's see if his girl is tough, too.
你们干什么
What do you want?
叫你挨… 挨…
How's that? How's that?
住手 你们住手
Enough! You've made your point.
干不干 快说
Does that mean you'll do it?
我求你们放了她
Just let her go.
我什么都肯干
I'll  do anything.
为了马子 什么都干
We won't
我们更不能放了她了
let her go unless you help us.
你们到底想干嘛
What do you want me to do?
你给我们收了钱 立刻放人
Collect the money for us.
我们是说一不二
Then I'll let you go.
怎么样啊
You don't have any choice.
好
OK
你别指望可以把电池拿掉
I wouldn't advise you to remove it.
任何一根电线断了 就会爆炸
Break one wire and the whole thing blows.
还有我按这个开关
The same thing happens
一样会爆
if I press this button.
从现在开始 你好自为之了
You'd better be careful.
家驹
Ka Kui.
小心
Be careful.
会回来的
I'll  come back for you.
有消息了
News.
追查电话来源
Track.
我找骠叔
I'll  get Uncle Bill.
钱准备好了没有
Is the money ready?
十分钟之内
We'llcollect it
我叫人上来拿
in ten minutes.
已经准备好了
It's ready.
又通知警方了
-Did you call the cops?
没有啊
-No.
哪里都找不到啊
We can't find him
不可能啊
How could
这时候他不会这么不负责任的
he be so irresponsible?
不等了
I can't wait.
听着 大家千万不要轻举妄动
Don't take any risks.
准备出发
Let's go.
Yes Sir
从这里来回 十五分钟刚刚好
You'll have ten minutes to get back here again.
别打什么歪主意
No tricks.
如果钱拿不回来的话
If we don't get our money,
你身上的炸药就会爆
your vest will go bang!
我们在这等你
We'll be waiting.
去吧
Get going.
祝你好运
Good luck.
我们来查案的
We're here to investigate
先生 你们…
Sir?
怎么
-Mr. Fung. -Chairman.
你们怎么知道的
Is that so?
坐
Have a seat.
既然你们允许我们接听电话
You promised to
就算你们私人电话
let us bug the phones.
只要你们用 我们就查得到
We could trace the calls.
你们查炸弹 怎么没那么大本事
It's too bad you can't handle
他们一收钱 我们立刻抓人
the bomb case so effectively.
希望你们不要把事情给搞砸了
I hope you won't do anything to make matters worse.
你们这么做 不等于帮着匪徒嘛
Because this will encourage the bombers.
既然警方帮不了我们
So the police couldn't help.
只有自己帮自己了
We could only depend on ourselves.
陈Sir 你上哪儿去了
Sir
陈Sir
Ka Kui!
- 陈Sir… - 走开
-Ka Kui! -Out of my way.
- 家驹 你干什么 - 走开 别挡着我
-Ka Kui!  Let me go!
- 你干嘛 - 别挡着我
Get out of my way!
- 陈Sir… - 家驹…
Ka Kui!
先生 你…
Excuse me!
家驹
Ka Kui.
家驹 你去哪儿了
Ka Kui, where have you been?
别问那么多了
Never mind.
我是来收钱的
What?
你是来收钱的
I'm here to collect the money.
你的手下
-Is he your man?
这是怎么回事啊
-Yes, he is.
我没时间了 钱呢 钱呢
money.
走开
Get out of my way!
- 你干什么你 干什么 - 家驹
-What are you doing? -Ka Kui!
不管你发生什么事
No matter what happens to you
你动手 我就开枪
Move and I'll shoot you.
千万不要开枪
Don't pull the trigger.
雷蒙 不要
No!
不信你就试试
Don't push me.
你一开枪
If you shoot me,
你跟骠叔就会死
everybody here...
你们大家都会死
...will be blown sky high.
我身上任何一根线路断了都会爆炸
If one wire breaks, the whole thing will explode!
家驹 到底发生什么事情
Ka Kui, what's going on?
你镇静点 我们一起解决
Can't we work this out?
十分钟之内我不出去 一样会爆
If I don't leave here in ten minutes, it will go off.
我没时间了
I don't have time!
不要追他
Let him go.
下面的弟兄听着
Attention all units!
看到家驹 千万不要拦着他
Do not stop Ka Kui.
家驹…
Ka Kui! Ka Kui!
不要过来
Don't follow me.
你们不要跟着我
家驹… 你干什么…
Ka Kui!
走开
Get out of my way!
家驹…
Ka Kui!
家驹…你干什么 家驹…
回来了
-I think he did it.
是啊
-Great.
好像有人跟踪 快走
-Looks like he was followed.
开车
-Let's go.
叫他过来
Tell him to move up.
把箱子给我
Give me the money.
有CID跟着我
I'm being followed.
我把他们甩了就回来
Let me shake them off first.
你们相信我
Trust me.
有条子跟踪吗
Are the cops behind us?
停车 别开过来
Stay back! Don't come near!
你怎么了 为什么停在这边
Why did you stop here?
干什么
-What are you doing?
搞什么鬼啊
-What's going on?
炸弹爆炸 快走啊
A bomb's about to blow. Run!
有炸弹 快走啊
A bomb! Run!
没人跟踪他啊
There's no cops!
是啊 耍我们
I'll blow him to bits.
炸死他算了
Wait!
你疯了 钱也会炸没的
What about the money?
哑巴说
And you can't get a radio signal in the tunnel.
无线电遥控在隧道收不到
那怎么办
What now?
放心吧
Easy
他马子在我们手上 不用理他
-We've got the girl.
回去再说吧
Don't worry.
用不着一起在这耗时间
-Let's go.
一个人等他
go.
有问题就把他做了
If anything goes wrong, kill her.
说
Where is she?
你们把阿美关在哪里
Where is May?
车子回来了
Look, he's back.
我说他不敢耍花招的嘛
I told you he wouldn't play tricks.
阿美
May!
嘘 不要吵
Quiet.
别动
Freeze! You're under arrest.
你们已经被拘捕了
Really?
拘捕 你怎么拘捕啊
Come on then,
来啊 过来拷我啊
arrest us.
不要动啊
Don't move.
不要乱来
不然我一枪一个
Move and I'll shoot you.
一枪一个
You think so?
有这么快吗
You'd have to shoot fast.
你他妈一枪三个吧
There are three of us.
如果我把你们抓回去
If I take you back
最多坐个十年八年
Ten or eight years at most
出来以后还有前途
And then you'll be a reformed person.
总比死得不明不白好
That's better than dying in this condition.
死得不明不白 总比挨穷好啊
Better to die
我们早就认命了
than to live as a pauper. We are ready.
想发财 没有错
There's nothing wrong with wanting to be rich
错在你们手段太残忍
The fault is that you are too cruel
什么是对 什么是错 发财专家
So what is right and what is wrong?
在这个社会
You can get
只要你们做的事 对大众有益
everything you want in life
谁都愿意给你们一份应得的报酬
by helping other people
你们不就发财了嘛
get what they want in life.
凭你们的体力和头脑 绝对做得到
You'd have a whole new outlook. That's what you should do.
但是你们所作所为
But what you have done
危害社会上每一个人的安全
now has hurt society.
违背所有人的利益
-This benefits no-one.
怎么违背所有人的利益了
-What does that mean?
你们想想
Other than you guys,
除了你们之外
who thinks you're
谁认为你们做的是对的
doing the right thing?
谁希望你们达到目的呢
Who would think highly of your purpose?
你全都对
You are right.
问题就出在这儿
Yes.
你说得很对
That doesn't sound too bad... but there's still one question.
如果有机会的话
We might take your advice
我们一定会试试你的方法
if we had certain opportunities.
所以我们不可以坐牢
See, we don't want to go to jail.
不可以受惩罚
We don't want to be punished.
不要逼我开枪啊
Don't push me!
不要乱来 全是炸药
Run! This is a fireworks factory.
阿美
-May!
家驹 我在这儿
Ka Kui.-I'm over here!
阿美 你没事吧
May, are you all right?
家驹
Ka Kui, be careful!
干得好
Good work!
家驹 快上来啊
Ka Kui! Come here! There's the rubbish chute.
那边有条输送带
There's an exit.
这些东西很危险的 快走
May, you go first.
这里好高啊
It looks too high.
高也得跳啊
Just jump!
家驹 你怎么样啊
Ka Kui, are you all right?
快走 阿美 快跑啊
I'm fine. Get out of here, May. Go as far as you can.
你小心点啊
Be careful.
阿爸 阿爸 我叫你给我爸
How do you like it? Want some more? Huh?
阿爸 阿爸…
How about some more, you little bastard?
我叫你爸 阿爸… 我叫你妈
Want some more?
阿爸 阿爸…
Want some more? Here!
阿爸… 我叫你他妈还爸
Want some more?
阿爸… 你他妈的给我爸
More?
糟糕
Shit!
家驹
Ka Kui.
别哭
Stop crying, okay?
你看 烟花多漂亮
Look. The fireworks are beautiful.